William F. Slavney

650 East Parkway South Memphis, TN 38104 (901) 321-3111 wslavney@cbu.edu

PRIMARY EXPERTISE: Practical Theology with a concentration on Catholic morality and ethical teachings of the Church. **SECONDARY EXPERTISE:** Systematic Theology with concentrations in Catholic spirituality, Christology, and Ecclesiology.

EDUCATION	
CHRISTIAN BROTHERS UNIVERSITY M.A. Education with Teaching License Candidate (Expected graduation May 2)	Memphis, TN
CHRISTIAN BROTHERS UNIVERSITY B.S. Chemistry & Physics Candidate (Expected graduation May 2023)	Memphis, TN
CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA Ph.D. Moral Theology/Ethics Candidate (Expected Graduation May 2020)	Washington, DC, DC
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE M.S. Nursing (2020)	Memphis, TN
UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE B.S. Nursing with Medical License (2019)	Memphis, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE M.A. Sacred Theology (2016)	Nashville, TN
AQUINAS COLLEGE B.A. Theology (2014)	Nashville, TN
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Saint Anne Catholic Church Director of Parochial Education	Memphis, TN Jan 2021 – Present
Music Director & Cantor	Jan 2021 – Present
Saint Cecilia Academy Part Time Campus Minister	Nashville, TN Jan 2021 – Present
Christian Brothers High School Part Time Campus Minister	Memphis, TN Oct 2019 – Present

Memphis, TN Apr 2019 – Present

Mountain Rest, SC

May 2020 - Present

Saint Francis Hospital

Nantahala Outdoor Center

Chattooga River Whitewater Guide

Part Time Emergency Multisystem Trauma Nurse

Christian Brothers University Adjunct Professor of Biology	Memphis, TN Oct 2020 – Present
Assistant to Health Services	Aug 2020 – Present
Associate Aquatic Director	Aug 2019 – Present
Director of Catholic Identity	Jan 2019 – Present
Professor of Religion and Philosophy	Jan 2019 – Present
Campus Ministry Associate	Aug 2018 – Present
Adjunct Professor of Religious Studies	Jan 2015 – Dec 2018
TI ADE 11	M 1: TNI
University of Memphis Interim Adjunct Professor of Biology	Memphis, TN Feb 2021 – May 2021
•	<u> </u>
Interim Adjunct Professor of Biology University of Saint Thomas	Feb 2021 – May 2021 Houston, TX
Interim Adjunct Professor of Biology University of Saint Thomas Visiting Assistant Professor of Biology Catholic University of America	Feb 2021 – May 2021 Houston, TX Nov 2020 – Jan 2021 Washington, DC, DC

CREDENTIALS & LICENCES

- Ordained into the Diaconate in April 2021
- (S.T.L) Licentiate in Moral Theology and Ethics from Catholic University of America
- American Red Cross Certified Lifeguard, CPR & AED, and Basic First Aid
- (R.N. & L.P.N.) Medical License & Registration TN, TX, MS
- (E.M.T) Emergency Medical Technician TN

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Memphis

Memphis, TN

- BIOL 4110 Science of Medicine
- BIOL 4150 Developmental Biology
- BIOL 4501 Virology
- BIOL 4635 Neurobiology

University of Saint Thomas

Houston, TX

- BIOL 3424 Comparative Anatomy
- BIOL 3436 Neurophysiology
- BIOL 3490 Developmental Biology

Christian Brothers University

- BIOL 109 Human Biology
- BIOL 211 Vertebrate Embryology
- BIOL 211L Vertebrate Embryology Lab
- BIOL 212 Comparative Vertebrate Anatomy
- BIOL 212L Comparative Vertebrate Anatomy Lab
- BIOL 213 Scientific & Medical Terminology
- BIOL 217 Human Anatomy& Physiology I
- BIOL 217L Human Anatomy & Physiology I Lab
- BIOL 218 Human Anatomy& Physiology II
- BIOL 218L Human Anatomy & Physiology II Lab
- BIOL 236 Nutrition
- BIOL 240 Bioinformatics
- BIOL 300 Pathophysiology
- BIOL 312 Human Physiology
- BIOL 312L Human Physiology Lab
- BIOL 367 Pharmacology
- BIOL 370 Toxicology
- BIOL 381 Animal Behavior
- BIOL 414 Animal Histology
- BIOL 414L Animal Histology Lab
- BIOL 416 Endocrinology
- BIOL 444 Hematology
- BIOL 444L Hematology Lab
- BIOL 451 Neuroscience
- BIOL 451L Neuroscience Lab
- RS 200 Understanding Religion
- RS 217 Old Testament
- RS 218 New Testament
- RS 220 History of Christian Thought: to the Reformation
- RS 221 History of Christian Thought: since the Reformation
- RS 230 Christian Ethics
- RS 245 Honors Religion and Science
- RS 254 Christianity and Peace
- RS 270 World Religions
- RS 280 Catholicism
- RS 285 The Church in the World
- RS 283 Lasallian Life from Beginning to Now
- RS 300 Jesus Christ
- RS 320 Religion in America
- RS 324 Christian Spirituality
- RS 330 Justice and Society
- RS 331 Spirituality of Ethics and Eating
- RS 340 African American Theology
- RS 345 God, Evil, and Suffering
- RS 355 Judaism
- RS 372 Women and Christianity
- RS 377 Apocalyptic Imagination

•	RS 380	Paul: His Life and Letters		
•	RS 385	The Gospels		
•	RS 392	Special Topics: The Rich Gift of Love		
•	RS 420	Catholic Spirituality		
•	RS 440	Christology		
•	RS 460	Moral Theology		
•	RS 490	Ecclesiology and Ministry		
•	PHIL 201	Introduction to Logic		
•	PHIL 220	Contemporary Moral Issues		
•	PHIL 224	Theories of Human Nature		
•	PHIL 223	Business Ethics		
•	PHIL 317	Ancient Philosophy		
•		Modern Philosophy		
•		Contemporary Philosophy		
•		Medical Ethics		
•		Catholic Biblical Studies (Graduate Course)		
•		Moral Theology (Graduate Course)		
•	MACS 699	Thesis (Graduate Course)		
Ca	Catholic University of America Washington, DC, DC			
•	TRS 357	Catechesis	vv usmington, De, De	
Co	llege of the	Holy Cross	Worchester, MA	
•		Introduction to the Comparative Study of Religion		
•		Mary in Christian Theology		
•		Introduction to Theology		
•		Angels and Demons		
•		Catholicism		
•		Understanding Jesus		
•		Contemporary Christian Morality		
•		Social Ethics		
•	RELS 147			
•		Judaism in the Time of Jesus		
•	RELS 190	History of the Early Church		

• RELS 203 Death & Afterlife

- RELS 219 Christian Prayer in Theory in Practice
 RELS 230 Theological Perspectives on Medical Ethics
 RELS 284 Sex, Money, Power, and the Bible

REFERENCES

available upon request.